i'm innocent today that you guys have
made in
uh... class fourteen directory
and that you
the research tools notes in their there
are a few meaning of this time we're
going to be doing
almost everything just from
philby creating coach today if you first
u_p_s_ data
and the notes
mostly just have instructions it down
when the data
my family
spend a little bit
time trying to you out for the day down
so we're gonna pretend that we got cut
off a good outcome in a cover-up to date
at the first
after reading for you guys or listening
depending on what you wanna read or
listen it's not very long
no up without
as a part of the ocean service for the
call podcasts
and so there's wings two mt three
audiophile or the transcripts
and if you click on this
you'll see there's a
a recent senate
notes that are actually
pretty well that's what we're doing
building a better deal is
so if that no achieved yada sisters met
talking about vertical datum
and we'll see some of that
hopefully on thursday we're gonna plot
that u_p_s_ from a group of all feeling
and we'll see
what is it scores on vertical accuracy
divorce and and thinking about this if
you go through
working with the g_p_s_ in here were
discovered the potato we're not going to
talk about the theory uh...
how a g_p_s_ works will be back for some
of your other classes
but this is just get background to have
in your head as you think about u_p_s_'s
so go ahead and
grant introduction here and there's
instructions on
v_e_ day dot
format copy mike did you get to me in
here
and pull them out there so if you look
here there's that didn't get it
into the clocks directory to grab
examples and the file is our
so there's the file in the u
to go ahead make sure you got that they
don't
and this is a visa to file so we could
be unzip it
reconnect after completing
you know i'm compressor data
foot take a quick peek at this data
by the end of the semester he should be
fitted seeing in the data fiercely
everywhere with our
our work unfortunately
now is the most fun
for st
lasts
it are pager
that we use good looking at possible to
do us me my dog
what we've got here is your favorite
soap arrived here
so you tend to break out so
csd
here just like we've seen before
separate up by commons but it's not
quite like the others csd data
with neema
attempt to start with
a dollar sign
you often see some stars were
exclamation point
there two letters that it
are called the talker
so this is g_p_ for g_p_s_ w lifer
weather
pc first i have no idea what
uh... and then after that comes from
water codes that say
the type of message
so here we've got wm he is a weather
message
hpc yet because
anti-g_a_t_t_ p_s_
and here's another weather message
deviated time message
insure that way
by uh... this class know if you put the
d_a_'s are about what did you hear about
the weather stuff is what was important
and we're gonna start
trailer parks or for the gta g_p_s_
tracked
there's lots of good information in here
it's got timestamp
it's got a lot of two
your hemisphere here longitude
hemisphere
and
some of the things i like the horizontal
pollution precision and vertical
position that
i know that thirty six point one of the
elevation of the info group
above sea level
or about that
ellipsoid
so we've got all information who's going
to get out about strengthening to some
place that we can plug because we can't
just say please plot
if
we've got a record impartial for it
social forces that lets guests ourselves
all list of
all of that nina messes that are in
so this could have
goes back to some of those things we do
that first homework assignment playing
with
this is the second time playing with
things like cut
so if we do ahead
name it outlawed yourself some examples
if we split
this on commons
and quite honestly we ought to use here
but we can do it cuts
dash d for the one letter
and common
and apt
one remember that
bash with cut
it's going to you
count from one but in python rosen
account from zero
so our first position here is position
one
and we can say
neema dot warding off but that the head
so we just get a little bit of it
and you'll see that that puts out
timelines argues messages
now if we're plays head
with swords
this or command
has it that you flight for unique
which says
only give us
each possible vert response once
so quickly and for are not
it's going to work a little bit longer
reasonable file
as they're yours all the any clients
if you see a message popping up saying
welcome to even to eleven ten
don't install of in time
if you do you know a special again puts
in
and still ahead in type
nasty
and space dash f one
and and and and pressed count
entered
three feet on the stuff
control c
at the affair
at the vertical bar
now space in manhattan
so there it is
high-tech history
circuitry
so you actually put the path
into your commands
seeded till two slash in your command
detectable prompt but i have their
condition of the command
survivor to separate out the prompt from
work
so if you're looking at the screen make
sure that
you see these lines here work starts
from here at the beginning
this is not a part of the command
fastest anywhere on that
if we want to find information about
you messages like this we can open on
firefox
and we can search for neema
t_g_a_
see what comes up
animate what you guys to g_p_s_ d
there is a famous hacker called eric
freeman
and he has put together
and opened documentation about
nema strings
the documentation for nema is about
for fifty dollars if you want to get
this information
i bought a copy because i had for you
i don't think you guys should have to
buy a copy
so if you click on that
it will give you a
a fairly detailed description of a lot
of the email messages
and you think you uh...
control after t_g_a_
it controlled units you get to you
the actual definition of
but that we won't
you want to keep this up but this is how
i found the documentation for gta
so talks about how
field number one is that you can see
time
there's one
right here
and you'll notice that u_p_s_ is are
supposed to have a very specific
like for example
hours minutes seconds and then fraction
the second and i
believe archaic isn't
exact format
so if we do less neema dot log
this do you have a report
gta
that will appear they actually don't
have a fraction of the second thing
there
so we're gonna write a purse or for this
particular instance gta
if you're trying to write software for
every g_g_ abt my run into you you have
to work very hard to be flexible because
every g_p_s_
violates the standard somewhere other
usually
so the vendors
we should be too much for this
results alone call them up and say
you're being bad
premium change
so we're going to go ahead and
were kinda parser for our particular
instance of it so we're not going to
order that all the little details
imagine attacking woodson's and you're
gonna break out all the pieces and
figure out how to live together
effect on its rightly so
person needs
when the soprano pieces in turn into
something that we can use
because the computer
also us
is a really annoying string
every time you look at if you have to go
look up in count how many columns over
and say
this one point one is what
and so for sir wilfred fell apart and
tell us exactly where everything is
and cover into useful
all right so let's go ahead and start
reading
harper sir
will call it
gta dot aren't
for pre-defined on file
inverter user typical user been yang the
papon
start for
python script
what's going to pick uh... random
message so we're going to refugee aid
this is kind of a fun way
play with this over into wordcount cm
and we've got to have got eighty six
thousand g_g_ age to play with
will do our head
ten thousand brand like go away into the
middle of the day and travel in the morn
stupidity look here
there's lots of zeros in our clients
campuses the hard work with
i think tale
florida grabbed the first ten thousand
lines with the head
and they were in a grabbed a lot
ten adults over base of driving ten
g_g_ aids in the middle of the file
somewhere
elliptical a number-one
depicted flavor one to me that's fine
so grab one of those lines
into an edit copy
and in are gta file state tests
g_g_ eight equals
and then
and in case of control wife
that line into your imax window
and one thing to remember is that
we want that all along the line so here
make sure that you have your and single
quote on the far right thereafter
uh... string
knock on the next one
um... close take a look at the top of
parent that that palin banging in the
your eye
you learn a lot of stuff prepared get
defensively together taking like if you
are mobile four languages thing timing
side challenging
uh... yet
if you see that you serving in the
pipeline after
enthusiastic
happy without this cost
at some of the year with pretty close to
this
albiric
do is slightly different here but i do
that video
you can go through that you'll see me do
all the pieces again video on you
let's go ahead and start
i've played violin
aman type right we don't need pile out
today but animatronic myself to you
if i leave dot that the pile abit
doesn't set up the plotting stuff
sorry math no for me
yet if you don't need the plotting stuff
i had my advertisement yet
so if we do you want
nl at sin here
in arrived by phone
you'll see that
we've got
archie g_-eight dot fi
and our name on stock
let's remind ourselves how do you think
like a little bit
if we can uh... import
models we can say imports gta
and tweaking type d_i_a_ are
teaching a whiskey is is that correct
reverting inside i think he invites all
which is our fight on file
i_q_ cdc that's a great one
i'll see if i can refer to set up europa
considering
so here i haven't saved there's two
stars down here
healthy for you the same thing
i don't
uh... so bc account violin here to start
the hash character account
that's at temporary
for a backup file that that he maxwell
generate
adult in an auto save after some points
once you say that those stars go away
deluxe control that's
benefit you and alex dash l you'll see
that there's
often they'll be a total filed a similar
backup file so cute
complete destroy your file box and
there's that there
there's also
if you've got to do the import the raw
also be a p y c
this is pipe on compiling your code you
can just ignore that file
of interest
so what you can view it as you can do
importance
t_g_a_
you haven't already
and one that we will back
if you take
something different in here
h_i_v_ import again nothing's going to
happen
import only does it once
optimized for and if you're actually
what we want to do if we have a changes
they reload gta and that will bring in
any changes that we have
and i fight on
and look a little bit different cells
every vote in the module
so still a jar again anti-g_a_t_t_
what's in there
mostly stuff we don't care about
liz underscores that were those but if
you see here is the tax gta
so we can say d_g_a_ period
have started yet so i just typed he
profound
anti-u_n_ terry and i fight on its gonna
print out a little strange sub it gives
us a string to work with
and we can start trying to break down
and pieces
than we've ever had a break
external problems
and important states gta
so if you out
the file so reflector home directory
any one of the interior your class
fourteen if you're not quite on so
your ipod iphone
near in there
any g_o_p_ dvd if we are in
fill the flash class
fourteen you may want to get there
you came to you
and b
swatch
cc stated in the home directory to
g_a_t_t_ apart
and then you can say
fill those slots klotz
fourteen
with regard to space
and artistic
so that what you move the file over
for the new place many can open it but
it he met
sofa dot gta test string
did anybody remember how trek apartment
csd string
axles split
so will do
d_g_a_ test
and we can say
thought split
we can ask it
how do we use it with a question mark
and we can say
so has the s_d_p_ or separator
sold to separate with the common
and give it a go so that
will break into fields forests
secure better go sleeping
split don't yep presidency right
now that house subspecies with slippery
sheriffs
a sneak preview of this much time
you can think you could actually say out
and then the number of in fairfield out
fourteen
and you have access to it so
anytime there's an alpine again i fight
on
it's going to say that someplace
so that's kinda he needs your just
playing around
florida coast forcefully do that
sastry get ready for
solo can do is we can say fields
equals
t_g_a_ god
uh... test g
pots plates
so if we do that battle senator variable
explicitly
does anybody remember back to manage to
see all the variables owner looked face
hepatic who u_n_ sometimes sees
something he really didn't expect
and i think it's impossible for a budget
and i finally figured out why
it's doing that sometimes because if we
tried to normally
it should work and tell us the list of
variables
what's happening as pile out
would you have accessed by lab is bring
in all kinds of stuff but it's stepped
on the move
so if we try percent two
you'll get the normal
by pipeline
and whose
you're the one of us are variables
there he sings called magic
functions inside abide by promises like
that ls command
they have a life span c l_ e_ since i
think things for you to make it easier
so you can always get
budget plans are actually a percent and
then some commands
and everything else is that make them
just enough percent so you can always
get them with the first time
answer who got clobbered by pile up
seek as a percent to
filled saying who's
is the same as per cent
los angeles appriciate got me he had he
confused for a couple classes and i
finally figured it out
we now have fields speak instead fields
and you'll see your list
and we can now access them by numbers
tickets a fields
and they said that uh... published a
mechanic access first one is the role
and the second one
is one
that's okay
one needs to period instead of a common
so you'd it'd be very careful
when you code any program
you have to be very careful with
punctuation and precision
so that works better
and if you actually want to use the
fields you have faith heal people
so you're going to you
summer hit control our research back
say fields
they control artwork finds like it
and dot
three and twenty four is the command
that iran perceptive feel terrible
so what you do a difficult up there
l taken char says the search back to
your history the control are answers
river search
and they needed to start taking some
part of
which you had so maybe gta
and it's now that i've been matching
into your history things that are gta
you can keep in control are
and we'll go back through previous
commands
and you can't control cd out about it
allotments there
so that we have
minus one
goes from the back end of this
field so that you fields
minus one reappear
tickets to the very last one
so my guess counts from the house right
hand side
so let's go ahead and take part
field commander we had here
read a copy of this
will go into a rematch
summer and i think that in there
the rates are building up
our function of the venom
deal to find him
so unless you want to create a function
gta
so we talked up close as last time
there's going to create a new function
called t_g_a_
and we will make a little bit different
safety code
gta
and then you have to intent to start
function
why did as i pressed enter right after
the uh...
alone there
and it will automatically intend for you
and we're gonna change this around here
this incident being our test message
today
have line coming is our argument are
facing some of the capacitor
some what line of taxes
and we're going to use a line dot split
ama com au
scientific fields
so we can start building up
so let's go ahead and start trying to
parse
part of its worst are up
you isn't doing the same and bite minds
yeah
yes so in here the gta types
thing it was not her is a helper to
fabric sample around select the type it
in the year
this is a local very well working on
we're going into the import module
driving the tough decision
to get a lot of proof
go back and forth the punch with that he
displays
so let's go ahead
play a little bit more on the upright on
side
so we've got our fields and fields um...
what number with the time when the
appear
what index about the uh... you know
one yes
so fields of one
looks something like that
so it's a series of six digits
and that's going to be our hours minsan
cyclists
so i'll just tell you
the formats as we go through them rather
than going into that document
and uh... firefox
so the transaction is going to be
three digits for the hour
food it is for the minute
and to do this for a second
so we need to break it into
these pieces
and turn it into an integer
so we want to jerk from that one
and that's going to give us some number
you haven't heard what the fields
you can just receptors to commemorate
their fight again
yet you can reading isn't anything you
want
if you are caught the over capital i
think it is that
yet and yet be really careful
i think you probably
yeah only split on the pier you have to
split on the problem
is this the f_e_c_ comma-separated
characters the comma
na period
so let's go ahead
and say
time
string
equals fields
so we've got a variable
that we can remember
a lot of times with programming
a key thing is not necessarily about
how few lines of coke and you're right
but how clear tenure cody
and if you read it later on can you
figure out what you were meaning
and things
like number of fields
really suck
because i look at the gta message
i think that's field mine
pratap account every single time and
during my p_h_d_
i lost it when i had table width like i
was doing what
com twenty six minus column twenty five
and my head explode
so i'd like to named fields i'd like to
be able to refer to them by and what
they are
in english
so if we say
whose
you'll now see the times during
is
just like that
so what will i do is put this into
those three pieces and turn them into
numbers
so the first thing we do is create a
verbal called
so please stay power
equals time strength
and as i've ever had a grab the first q
characters office stirring
if it's like a less
fearful and that's close
also square brackets are your
uh... array of dressers
or lista dressers
a colon
so it goes from beginning range standing
range here
so if we leave off
the left hand side all-star from the
beginning
i remembered that we need to these list
of strings
it's going to go up to you but not
including the number so if we've got
uh... so up here we've got zero two four
six
so zero too
or sixes
if we say
colon
this is that position one
first right this is a position zero one
and five
cohen two senators we're gonna go from
the beginning
out to britain or including
so it's just operate here
that's going to get zero point
visit one of things we did i do a whole
bunch of these are getting used to it
and if you go he's our programming
language that don't count from zero
like this
nicotine
uh... might not help from zero
so go ahead and try it out and then just
say our
and hopefully see zero two
favors he was wrong with our zero two
the food we don't really want to come
back
yet this election zero there and he
knows what's around there are two
too little
single quotes
that's a string so please stay tight
to get back a strain
together working with our phone number
if we don't want a string of if we want
the actual number
so you could use a map of the time
and we can always converts pestering
by just a hint
or for wonderful of you could say float
so then you get back
the number two
so what we really want
rather than what we have in thirty one
here
this turned into a string
would rather go back up to that
who want to say
take that whole stringing out back
and turn into an answer
we cross our fingers and hit enter
that detect our
you get back just the number two pretty
tight
power
photography
it finance
will get one
busy road part of the string
so if you want to be able to do it for
about the time
festering is not very helpful began
researching map on the string it's going
to compare character numbers
and i don't want that
so let's go ahead and
try to put this into our function
over here on the lot
some of the copy this part
so here's a really is that history
command to go back and see what i was
doing
through history
and we can the thing that he'll do it i
i thought i because it's a place to just
try and play
and try to find how to do it by going to
you
three up on the documentation howdy
things
so right here at times during equals
feels those whom we grabbed that out
uh... fifty-year-olds as we have these
uh...
matter ten different things that can
copy that one
and completely here
so what we've done
if we take
this long straight hair
we're gonna pass it into our function
and wine
we're gonna break in the pieces with the
split like we did before will say that
into a very vocal fields
then we're gonna go and work with the
old bit by bit renting each of the
sections are going to figure out a deal
with each one of them
at source a time string equals and we'll
grab healed one
you could
always just work with this
but if you come back in a couple months
and try to read this
and you're dealing with the old one two
three
it's getting a confusing like to see i
do that in that video was
ecstatic that a lot harder for the cult
so now
field one here coming out was
so if you want to missus field's zero
the section is are a little bit of time
so that'll be a nice time string
variable
and we can take the our about by
grabbing the first few characters and
turning into a number
like picking up extra memory or anything
but the times right
you you know
yet willard work there
don't worry about speed or memory
the goal here re-reading code
to unfortunate phrase call premature
optimization if you try too hard
to make things clever in fancy first
yeah it's very unfortunate
if you try too hard to make things bmc
at first
all you're doing is your hurting
yourself time-wise
difficult
the expensive part uva computing system
is you
you cost way more than a computer at the
computer has to work the next draft
seconds
that's the computer problem
every moment you sit there
you cost
yourself or
your boss or your company or whatever
the time to be there
and at the computer has to work a lot
harder because
we wonder were quick
to get things going and it was easier
for us
and that's what does the computers
problem if it's going to work hard
we don't care
so in this case we're going to do
everything we can to abuse the computer
and make our lives easier
if you see some of the car that i write
for production stuff after i've figured
out how to do something all come back
and write code
there's times i can barely breathe when
i'm doing
from doing everything to trick in the
book because i'm processing
terror bytes of data
as fast as i can try to keep up with
something
it's more about
kelly right clear coach in the fall of
what we've done
and can you bring it in six months
and if you ever think that you
brightcove
and that you'll just get it when you
come back
try putting coat away for a year to come
back a long time about its it's almost
like someone else velvet most the time
even if you get the job
you have to treat the codes if you're a
is written by someone other than to try
to understand
so let's go ahead and
paprika statement to see the cells they
print power
were not aware that trevor turned in a
back room
like that yet
you it will make it even better will put
prints to make it
bolstering our colon in quotes
followed by our house
so hopefully this works right we're
gonna see
our colin printed out and then a number
right after it
so i'm gonna go ahead and try to run
this function and hopefully we got to go
this is taking all the pieces that we've
had
up till now all of our lectures and
trying to pull them together into
actually doing something
sourcing of real world
d_g_a_
if you have it in fact there's somewhere
we will show up in here
as a
sort of problem
and we can now run are functions and g g
eight
decode
p_g_a_
and here now that a pass in
some line of text
eighty five days
anemic string in here
we've made our lives easier by sticking
a spots one around we can use so we can
say
in here will say
uh... t_g_a_ dot
and in town
so we're gonna grab that string that we
have saved
as a test message or ask how fat
that make sense
once you get it should be fairly obvious
i'm just trying to be really obnoxious
my fifty if you can see
uh... you don't
the spaces are required in this
this language
and bash we have all kinds of space
missions
the only spaces impact on that really
matter of time army indentations
to break
tentar
and hopefully you see our colin too
and lindsay are going to
yeah
so let's go ahead and trying to parse d
within the hour
let's do them into the second
so did you removed
i'm gonna keep saying this guy's it's
hearsay can hear me say
witty max
always take a look to see if you stayed
if you see two stars
in that bar at the bottom of your file
it means you have it saves
and it's no matter how much it tight
if you have a state it's not going to
appear in new york
in your run
the processes
typically
you're right code
feature you save
noel
stars
and then you reload
your module
and then you can run irtrad-l function
here
security ye
he
people at it's already here hotfix
requested
so inside this functions
we're trying to make that function the
generic so if for any strength
dysfunction doesn't know anything about
that string if you notice
there's no catheters for gta anywhere in
here
it's taking in something called wine it
doesn't know what that is until you call
it
so here
we're going to call the deco g_g_ a
function
we have to pass it in the past d_g_a_
so they know was deceitful
and we can grab that
from the model of self salute
for taking a back out of this
animal calling the function of passing
it back in that okay
him
uh...
yes so
the fact that in here
since there is no text each year inside
that function it doesn't actually know
anything really about that
you could
it might be able to support to see it
like this because they decode
g_g_ aid
kit yeng
and if we think that
weekend say iran
g_g_
in here
what this will do is it'll start up
load this file
as their work from top to bottom panel
think testy g_-eight low this date of
walk
so that's a that's touring in this
variable
as conveyed to find a function
blow that up
and that's what i call the code gta
with that parameter and it
we could also just pass it
we could also just take this guy right
here
and call it
help out a little bit senior couple
different ways
work we're doing the same thing like
four different ways better
the thing about this is that were using
a psd files for both left with a few
things contained together
we have tested inside the file the teens
typically when you get this later on
you'll be loading date out of a file or
pulling it from the network someplace
enable
had passed the g_-eight you please
describe the alice someplace
and so i think that functions and please
poles apart in return
the accident while walk for that
if you have a trailing comma
it's kinda weird
so let's go ahead
star decoding
all of the different park
let's go back to us by phone here and we
have the time strength
and let's go ahead and parked out units
and the fact that
so will say
equals
and then we need to start times during
what numbers do you guys think
are going to be
for pulling out the minutes
trigger is close to import
two and three
so then you specified to colin four
because you know that the second one
second but we don't go we go up to but
not including
uh... numbers to corn four
and print
and one thing
search engine head back out member for
here notice there's no allegation type
print
at least five minutes
there's the outstanding for that
out forty five
so let's go ahead and copy this kind
just so you know a lot of professional
programmers code exactly like this
they work with my fight on a trite
things out
annotation into their code as they go
told the okay wait up to two right
column
you might see people sometimes will
right under tons of stuff in the try to
write later on
they also sometimes the same people have
a lot of problems
trying at that
huge waffle co homework grade
uh... that would be good idea
like this
so if we try that again group earings
double-check that works
summertime
minutes
and then type
minute picture is in danger
excellence
and now he's using four seconds so
oftentimes are raking short
if you agree vietnamese am i and was a
lot of people to
that's the same has the functioning
or minimum out some west
i so i recommend not using am i and the
search work for me
others is often nice to be able to take
place that sets a dangerous one
so will say seconds understand recreated
f_c_c_
will do the antigen
and time stirring
and he wants to learn some of the
numbers from here
for colin excellent so that was
start from
position four
and go to the end
it also said
for colin sex
phil to do that print
feels pretty good
is view
fit
yes if you are to be more generic your
purchase trying to work toward a
specific
if you try to write an actual parser for
all these years
it's going to be about ten times as much
colorful today
as you have to check out all sorts of
craziness
which is why it's often gives you the
library with someone else has taken a
long time printouts
subdued copying
if that in
so now what's create not print statement
that says
all of our different things so minutes
and i'll get my a c stay consistent
soap with you that that should hopefully
print out our hours minutes seconds so
we should see
to for our powers
forty six for our minutes
and
thirty-four for arc seconds
let's go ahead and fight run
t_g_a_
none of us i'm not getting every vote
right now because we've added this
decode invited here
so if we preload
that it's always going to do the same
thing
it gets a little confusing when you have
actual running code
in a marginally try to import
flicking comment that out in the kids
detective reporting to comment
and then reloaded
it doesn't have a weird like
running as it's going
animate continue
g_-eight diet
go back to that
http
died
and
read
so do you agree well
both so you're just playing around with
it so here
in thirty eight needed me equals time
strings
uh... so you've basically was for a
while to that same command at the intuit
uh... because there was a teenager
suffered from each other
what happens in atlantic city
yet so when you're working with local
variables
so that's the key thing
these variables in here
our local so that's faltering
they don't exist anywhere else but
inside of there
so we have a variable overhear life
seconds equals
this as the sea
and these f_c_c_ have nothing to do with
each other they live in different worlds
so something like if we go we've done it
anodes go grab some other g_g_ he's back
here
so something like decoding
t_g_a_
so here you'll see what the first one
should have thirty four in the next week
at thirty eight
so if we say
rundown
i'll come out with seconds thirty four
and accenture secretary
that make sense
all right sir now let's go ahead and
where it is in a little more time with
time because
finds interesting but not
we would really want know where we are
so we want to take
this part
a b g g a stern
everyone turn those characters into
our last year longitude
and this is where
i kind of
felt like thima
finally fired a lot
is the kind of song
so they've got
forty-three
and then
hockey
period
twenty sixty swim team six
long has more
with a car
baskets your latitude
that's not a lot to be anybody really
walk
what all sears
brisburg is here at byu degrees food
forty three degrees
and it's very clear
is
decimal
minutes
whoever did that
they could have just given us
decimal
degrees
and we could just let it up and went on
but they weren't you all about the work
for the rest of your life who will be
harder every time you might have voted
for this stuff
thanks guys itself
here find stuff like this all throughout
the standards and somebody had a really
great reason they convinced everybody
else on the committee to get there is
that this is a great idea
an islamic
this gives us extra practicing writing
little parker so when when i say parser
we want decimal degrees other pets
operating at berkshires picking his
weirdness
and returning
right number if it's just a duffel
degrees floating point number
so we can just plug on a mac
what so we're going to go ahead and try
and do that
so what typically do it functions
this is a great time for a blank line
so ice you know i have read
fuji ones of the bond
what was done here
you don't have something like that
so when you when it it's going to
say that very bored
creek dysfunction and there's nothing
went to bed
yet would still have to do a decode
eugene block
all right so what's right
and break them apart so we're gonna
to back here in tight fields
to remember what we have in our fields
and so feel zero was our little gta
header part
field one was our time
feel to you
everything except for the and for more
so will say
lapse during
equals fields
and
so hopefully
that should capture that for us sold
five lobstering
yes
if this is a style thing we don't have
the viewer
you can do it you don't have to do it
in here are doing it because if i just
for a black you might think about the
death motive replied to you
and by putting it underscores tiara it's
like
bt over the head of his clustering and
it's not what your end result is going
to be
out sometimes
you see this just to be like if not just
the obvious what you do
your code
you'll find some cardinal driving up
some people think that is just too wordy
and it gets in the way
i'm hoping here it helps you guys out
and remember that that's a string
i think that they wouldn't do that my
color
i would hope that in the context it sees
a string
my function is a very long so you could
remember it but if
if your concerts getting more full pages
you'll have to do stuff like this
which is also realizing for code
ever function of multiple pages
he probably has something wrong
anything is longer than a page is hard
to follow
yes i try to read a story remember all
the pieces
and you gotta keep jumping back to look
at the front part thanks confusing
yale seed
you'll see pics like the check some part
here's this little weird thing on the
end that you have to calculate some
number based on all the facts
i break that as a separate function i
stick it someplace else and you'll see
that talk like excel
so let's go ahead
hands
get ready for this
so that's a lot of she is a comment
ambitious gives you a hint that this
whole section is going to be about
latitude
animal copy n our little
lobstering q
theirselves set up here
so it's going try and break this apart
and turn into what we need
to get our y value
so if we save lives during
which part
artery going to put in here to get that
to you
degree part out at forty three
and square brackets
yep i hear several correct answers he
could do zero colin too
is one way
or you believe that the royal
enter
you get back to forty three
we want to get injure from that's right
soul
we can do you
brackets is the first part
our degrees thirty four off the degree
part
now we want to deal with this dot the
more minutes
ross who is a thanks guys for making our
lives acta difficult
so while string
how do we get the rest of it
killed off the first to you
before work you off the back up
to cooperate on
so there's the backdraft
now for call into on that
it gets very unhappy with that because
there's a decimal in there
so that was the rope
eight-point stockton coll entities says
i'm sorry i don't really allowed us to a
place is in in hers
so piss off
so what we want to do is we want to call
loans
so there's our national float
but they've where life difficult they're
trying to cause it to have both on the
coast
if we add
that number eight point one two six
eight two the forty-three we do not have
printer
because that's
minutes
that's not that's more victories which
was like
they would know how to convert from
minutes
to degrees
in latin
divide by
so we want to divide up by sixteen
so that gives us her death all part of
the degrees
so now we've got all of our pieces
together we gotta go find them all
including together
yet he didn't need it ideas do stuff
like habit
what happens is if you want
if you take few injuries and divide them
even if it were grounding problem
i type of period to make this a floating
point number two
to guarantee
i didn't need to because i've already
said this is a float
so we're okay so if you try to take to
enters
secrecy example
he said
fifty-nine divided by sixteen
immediate zero
which is not what we want to get so if
we do period them again a floating point
number
i do a lot of a defensive coding things
weren't trying to protect myself to make
sure i don't make a stupid mistake
because i've made so many stupid
mistakes in my life coating that
do you feel weird
unlike a lot better
so let's go grabber pieces for him to
steal a history again
and let's go find our front porch
which was sixty one for me
folded edit
copy and edit paste
amber add to it
the second part the decimal
portion
so hopefully
presenter
and we get
hired us the mall
so that there were a lot of u_s_a_
wayy equals
and now we have state so
print copy dot
and paste this craziness
right there
so unfortunately
we couldn't just say something like that
worry just did that
inter afloat and then some strength
and just turn it rain to number one
we have to do some fancy
coming apart henry going to gather all
pieces
the gta message is a great way to learn
how to deal with strings and pull things
apart
in terms of uh... designed message i'd
give it up
pretty portrayed
what if that's next field so put
garfield's here
we just use this one
which was number two
this parade here and for north
if we have to pass
what we need to do u r y value
if you're allowed to use in the southern
hemisphere
how do you represent that as a dot some
of the green number
negative yes we need to say why equals
and we we won't do it on this one but
for the west to east west on what was he
will do that for sure
so what would say it again
fields
so with animals that
zeroed blown too
yes three
equals
paths
why equals
negative what
forty three times minus warner have
really right foot this time
so let's go ahead and
i get rid of this guy and analyst try it
out
source they print
too
furman go ahead and use the line-item
and again to our run
we've got are nice
decimal add to that we can actually use
encoded effect
on thursday ten or mister lynch kind you
want to reflect
on thursday i'm going to pre bills
underrated to load up of latitude
longitude
everything that's in the gta
and we're gonna go used up all of them
were up
what happens g_p_s_
and also from forever moreno watched
house true that u_p_s_ on the roof is
and see if it's any good
and how much we can't trust the fact
so now we're gonna do
though was it in
thirty while it is
stuff here
seats can be very similar but not quite
exactly the same
so we're going to have zero
seven
zero
five six
period
your favorite full stop
three seven six one
how much andrew w
before we had two digits number have
revisits here
and then this is going to be
this is our degrees
and this is art
decimal
minutes
soaring to all of these activities
over at the change or two to three
just like that a little bit around
and so in my co-chairman of strings
speed this up so we can
keeping a pie for people back
i'm gonna put another comment after a
blank line and say
wanted to
just to give ourselves and visual space
between latitude longitude
will say long
stirring
fields
and graphic account again
here grow into a split so control x
too
and this is when things get long day
tend to be no fun
so it's right next to us their mind
so we can we can say
this is your own
one
too
so we'll try to overhear each day
fields
so that's good i guess the long string
just like we had before where
surety very much like what we didn't
hear
the change it around for our
longitude
so will say acts equals
hello and political eighty as to your
prophetic grabbing the first two
characters for the grab the first
three characters so three
so that's going to give us
uh... zero seven zero
the degrees portions
we're gonna add to that but that's small
minutes parts will save floats
and hello i am
stirring
and again we gotta start from the third
characters go to the end
and divide by fifty
for the period against other
let's go ahead and say friends
longitude
acts
colin
come on and and acts
let's try running mac
beget occurred we missed it and that's
something
here with the signs were in the western
hemisphere
this election is negative
so we have to check for
that w here
just like we checked appears will say
fields
five so one passed or or we're just
forward equals
what's
exit equals
negative ads put this line there
now here on it
we get minus seventy point nine
and hopefully if you put this in a
mapping program it'll have a point right
on the roof of this building
and if not
but i checked it
so thats
the basics of parsing
when you've got four map there's almost
always something
annoying gainer way people do funny
things
and parsing it all about undoing all
those on things that you don't want
entering into
simple data that you can
parts a whole file full of these g_g_
eight-week and then get that position
uh... g_p_s_ over time
and look and see the warner
that u_p_s_ stability number
which isn't perfect
but hopefully is pretty good i haven't
done the numbers yet to see how bitter
g_p_s_ is but by the end of thursday
will make a plot that she tells you know
in the number of leaders
how far that
g_p_s_ trips during the day
so then when you go out and you take a
position of the g_p_s_ and hit the
button right down the numbers
you have a sense of what a g_p_s_ can do
with one measurement
and how far off it might be
use g_p_s_ will be a slightly different
value how much is there might be
but which will know that one
you have a sense of what what can be
sadat point watch videos
eleven twelve and third
eleven through fourteen for teens going
up today
it's currently trying to
in my office trying to remove every week
he is noise data recorder voice
i can't make a more videos in this
building prisons theological more
efficiently
watch this video as you'll see
very much the same thing
that video notes have detailed examples
going through
all the stuff all the way up through
including the g_p_s_ wonder plot
and on thursday will look at the data
and more how to make some nice figures
in that part left with titles on things
the nice part about that because the
data will be great if you know when you
fifty dollars in this part
you can put off
jeanette figured out till later on
i thought maybe you have to get it back
into parts
amici degrade into the plodding through
slowed up a file get going
within a target and corrected to be
without things like decimal minutes and
fine